Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're talking about
one of our favorite
topics here at EnglishPod.
That would be food. We love
talking about food and this
time we are going to pick
up some food at the deli.
Oh, what's a deli? A deli is a special
store where a person can buy meats.
Okay. Meat and cheese.
And in this case we're talking
about special meats. It's
not just like pork or beef.
Right. You could also buy the butcher.
It is cured meats, cold meats.
So let's take a look at
today's vocabulary preview
to find out more about
this special kind of meat.
Very cabaret-y preview.
Alright, so at the deli you
usually pick up cold cuts. Cold cuts.
So basically the way that I
used to remember cold cuts as
a child was that cold cuts are
what you put on a sandwich.
So sliced turkey, sliced
chicken, ham, ham, salami.
Okay, like pepperoni would be a cold cut.
That's right. So cold cuts are
meats that you serve cold normally.
They're usually cured.
They're not like raw
pork or raw beef. You
put them on a sandwich.
So cured meats would be like that
they're smoked. They're not cooked.
No, they're not cooked.
You're right. They're smoked
or they're cured with the
kind of chemical or brine.
That means that they're preserved.
They can last for a long time.
Alright, very good.
So that's what we're getting at the deli.
Usually at the deli you can pick up
meats, cheeses and pickles and all that.
All of that good stuff.
Alright, so why don't we jump into our
dialogue and listen to it for the first time.
Honey, we're all out
of wine and cheese.
Do you mind running to the
deli and picking up a few things?
Can't wait.
I'm watching the game right now.
Your friends and family
are coming over tonight
and we still need
to get a lot of things.
Fine. What do you need?
Okay, pick up some cured
meats to go with the wine.
Maybe a pound of Polish
sausages, ham, liverwurst,
salami and any other
cold cuts that are on sale.
I think I saw a promotion for pastrami.
Also, get some coleslaw
and a jar of olives.
Whoa, wait a minute.
It's not a bit too much.
I mean, how much is all this going to cost?
Never mind that. Get some dips as well.
Get a jar of spinach and blue
cheese dips and also some satsiki.
If they have been dipped, get that as well.
Last but not least, get some pickles.
Is that all your majesty?
Very funny. Get a move on.
People will be here any minute.
All right, we're back. So now we're
going to go into language take away.
We're going to take a
look at six key words.
Language take away.
All right, so the first key word that we
have, we actually talked about it already,
but just to make sure that you
got it, those are cured meats.
Cured meats.
Well, to cure something
is to preserve it in this case.
So be careful because to cure
has a couple of different meanings,
but when we're talking about food,
something that is cured is preserved.
For example, pickles are
cured in salty water, brine.
Oh, is that what it's
called, brine salty water.
Yeah, no wonder I don't like pickles.
But pickles are like, if
you don't put them in
brine, they don't taste
all soury and nasty.
No, that's because they're cucumbers.
So a cucumber becomes a
pickle after it's been cured.
So we could talk about pork, but
when pork is cured, it becomes ham.
Okay, so cured meats
are meats that have
been preserved through some kind of
process, like using salt or drying them.
Okay, awesome.
And one of these cured meats,
I think maybe is a liver worst.
Okay, well, this is a German lesson
now, not just an English lesson.
In English, we have a lot of
words to come from German.
And one of these words is worst.
Okay, and that means sausage, right?
That's right, sausage.
So brought worst, liver worst.
And in this case, liver
worst, I'm sure you
can guess what part of
the pig that comes from.
Liver.
Very good, Marco.
You got to start for the day.
Awesome.
Yeah, no, liver worst is a kind of sausage
that's made up of this part of the animal.
Okay.
Actually, I've never, I don't
know if I've had liver worst.
What does it look like?
Is it white?
Is it red?
Is it, I think it's like dark,
light, purplish, whitish.
I don't know.
I've had blood worst.
That's good.
Yeah, blood sausage is delicious.
Okay.
And, well, apart from
picking up meats and cheeses
at the deli, you can
also pick up coleslaw.
All right, coleslaw is an American classic.
I'm sure you could get this
other places as well, though.
It's basically a cold salad that's made up
of cabbage and carrots and maybe onions.
But generally, the sauce is white.
It's like a mayonnaise and vinegar sauce.
So it's very stringy, lots of thin,
long pieces and the sauce is white.
Okay.
Yeah.
I think this is a very American thing.
I'm not really sure
if I've seen coleslaw
in many other places, but
I personally don't like it.
Again, because of the whole vinegar thing,
I'm not a big fan of the bitter stuff.
Yeah.
I love, we also call it
slaw, sometimes with
a side of slaw, I love a hot
dog with a side of coleslaw.
Oh, really?
Favorite meals.
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
Interesting sauce.
It's Greek, I believe.
That is correct.
And I'm not going to try
to pronounce it because
I might mess it up, so I'm
going to leave that one to you.
Well, I don't speak Greek, but
this is how we say it on America.
Satsiki.
Okay.
Satsiki is a food that comes
from Greece, like you said.
You know, in America, we have a lot of
different foods in Europe, too, wherever.
People come from all over the place, and in
America, we've adopted a number of foods.
One of these foods is Satsiki.
It's a white yogurt tip.
Okay.
So usually in Satsiki,
there is some onions,
some cucumber, some
pepper, but it's a really
good, thick, creamy yogurt dip
that you use with bread or chips.
Okay.
And that's actually our next word.
You mentioned it's
a dip, so you're using
that as a noun, and
that's our next word dip.
Dip.
So basically, a dip is a kind of
food that you eat with other foods.
Okay.
So it's like a sauce.
Exactly.
Or finger food.
So basically, a dip is a food you eat with
other foods, so you can have chips and dip.
That would be potato chips with dip.
And sometimes you have
tomato dip or cheese dip.
In this case, we have
Satsiki or blue cheese dip.
Blue cheese dip.
Okay.
But actually, it's also a verb, right?
Two dip.
So when you take your potato chip and
you dip it in the dip, you can say that.
Yes.
Dip it in the dip.
Okay.
So you dip your potato chip in the dip.
Yes.
So, those are all the
words that we have for
you today on language
takeaway, why don't we
go back, listen to the
dialogue again, and
we'll be back in a bit
with fluency builder.
Honey, we're all out of wine and cheese.
Do you mind running to the
deli and picking up a few things?
Can it wait?
I'm watching the game right now.
Your friends and family
are coming over tonight,
and we still need
to get a lot of things.
Fine.
What do you need?
Okay.
Pick up some cured
meats to go with the wine.
Maybe a pound of Polish
sausages, ham, liverwurst,
salami, and any other
cold cuts that are on sale.
I think I saw a promotion for pastrami.
Also, get some coleslaw
and a jar of olives.
Whoa.
Wait a minute.
Isn't that a bit too much?
I mean, how much is all this going to cost?
Never mind that.
Get some dips as well.
Get a jar of spinach and blue
cheese dips and also some Satsiki.
If they have been dip, get that as well.
Just but not least, get some pickles.
Is that all your majesty?
Very funny.
Get a move on.
People will be here any minute.
Alright, we're back.
And now let's take a look at
three key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Alright, this first one is a
very, very common phrase.
We use this a lot
in English and we're
maybe running late or we
need something very quickly.
We say, "Hey.
" Can you run to the
store and get this?
Or do you mind running to the deli?
So the verb here is to run to.
Run to.
Run to the deli.
Now, does this mean that you're actually
going to walk very fast to the deli?
You're going to run?
No, this is not literal.
This is not... Okay.
I'm going to go to the deli.
I'm going to get some food.
Now this is going quickly.
Okay.
So, I could say, Marco, I have no time.
Can you run to the store
and get me some milk please?
Okay.
Please just go really quickly in your car,
your motorcycle, anyway, anywhere you can.
Or walking?
Yeah, exactly.
Good.
So that's run to the
store, run to the deli.
In this case, we saw it in the sentence,
"Do you mind running to the deli?
" So, do you mind going quickly?
So, this is going quickly.
Do you mind running to the deli?
This is a thing that we can do.
Okay.
And so, she was telling
him what to get and he's
like, "Whoa, this is going
to be really expensive.
" And she answered
with this phrase.
Never mind that.
Okay.
This is a phrase that we use when
we want to say, "Don't worry about it.
" That doesn't matter.
No problem.
It's not important.
So, never mind.
You could say by itself.
Never mind.
Forget about it.
But never mind that is like
saying, "This argument is over.
It's not a problem.
" Okay.
So, never mind that.
As I was saying, let's go to the store.
Okay.
Good.
So, it's not important.
It's irrelevant.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
Very good.
And the last phrase that
we have for you is a very
interesting phrase when
the girl said, "You know what?
Very funny.
" But get a move on.
People will be here any minute.
Get a move on.
So, as we often say here at
English Pop, this is a kind of
phrase we have to look at as
a chunk, as a unit, as one piece.
Right.
You could say, "Get me this."
Or, "I moved.
I moved my house.
" But, "Get a move
on" means, "Hurry up.
" Hurry up.
Start leaving now.
Go.
Go to the store.
Be quick about it.
So, this is a command.
Get a move on.
Okay.
So, take it as a phrase, just like
you know the phrase, "Hurry up."
Or, "Go quickly.
" Remember the phrase, "Get a
move on," as a way of saying, "Come on.
Quickly.
Go.
" That's right.
Or, as I always say,
when I'm with friends
and we're, you know,
going slowly somewhere,
say, "Hey, guys,
let's get a move on.
" Let's get a move on.
They're going to close.
Let's get going.
Let's go here.
Okay.
Very good.
So, get a move on.
Let's get a move on.
And, why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue for one last time.
Honey, we're all out of wine and cheese.
Do you mind running to the
deli and picking up a few things?
Can it wait?
I'm watching the game right now.
Are friends and family
are coming over tonight
and we still need to
get a lot of things?
Fine.
What do you need?
Okay.
Pick up some cured
meats to go with the wine.
Maybe a pound of
Polish sausages, ham,
liverwurst, salami, and any
other cold cuts that are on sale.
I think I saw a promotion for pastrami.
Also, get some coleslaw
and a jar of olives.
Whoa.
Wait a minute.
Isn't that a bit too much?
I mean, how much is all this going to cost?
Never mind that.
Get some dips as well.
Get a jar of spinach and blue
cheese dips and also some satsiki.
If they have been dipped, get that as well.
Last but not least, get some pickles.
Is that all your majesty?
Very funny.
Get a move on.
People will be here any minute.
All right, we're back.
So now, Catherine, I
understand you're a big
fan of pickles and
olives and all that stuff.
I love cured food.
Pickled.
Have you ever had a pickled tomato?
I hate pickled tomatoes.
Pickled tomatoes, pickled
pickles, pickled olives, everything.
I love it all.
I hate-- actually, there are a
couple of things that I really like.
For example, coleslaw, you
mentioned that it has cabbage in it.
And many people may know this
vegetable as this purple lettuce, right?
It looks like a lettuce, but purple.
That's right.
I don't like it.
And I actually hate olives and pickles.
I can't really eat them.
Sounds like you don't like bitter things.
Like vinegar.
Yes.
Yeah, no.
Not a big fan.
Not a big fan of anything that's bitter.
I love it.
It's one of my favorite.
I love salty foods and I love bitter foods
and that's all I have to say about it.
I've never really
understood how people have
like a whole pickle and they take it
out of the jar and they just bite into it.
It's like-- Well, the adjective to
describe a pickle's flavor is sour.
Sour.
It's very sour.
And in America, at delis, you
can buy full sours or half sours.
Oh, really?
Some pickles are less sour than others.
We call it a half sour.
My favorite pickles are full sours.
Really?
Make cry a little bit.
Is this the whole pickle thing?
Is this very American?
Because you always have pickles
and burgers, for example, right?
You've got a McDonald's.
You have pickles and burgers.
Is this very American or is
this coming from another place?
It comes from Europe, a lot of German
food involves pickles, pickled vegetables.
The Koreans, also,
Korean food has a lot of
people, but it's like kimchi,
which is pickled cabbage.
And so, in Chinese culture
as well, a lot of pickled foods.
So I think this is something
that's very common
all over the world and
you can have pickled fish.
Really?
Yeah.
And you can pickle anything.
I don't know if we pickled
things in Latin America.
This is why it seems very strange to be.
But this is a really
interesting topic, why don't
you let us know what your
favorite cured meats are.
I know there are a lot of different types.
And if you like pickles
or not, maybe some
people out there will support
me and say they don't like pickles.
All right.
And if you have a delis in
your home country, let us know.
I've always been curious about this.
Do you have delis?
Or do you just have a butcher shop?
What's the difference?
Awesome.
So we'll see everyone there.
EnglishPod.com.
Until next time.
Bye, bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]